《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情概要
NARRATOR: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
菲斯克上校是珀加索斯新任指挥官
ADAMA: Col. Fisk is the new Pegasus Commander.
这个赛隆婴儿血液中没有抗原
The Cylon's fetus contains no antigens.
这使它成为一个万能供血者
It makes it a universal donor.
你是说你找到了治疗总统癌症的方法?
ADAMA: Are you saying you've found a cure for the President's cancer?
是的
BALTAR: Yes.
有些船只得到一半配给
ROSLIN: I've got ships on half-rations.
那些补给…
When will some of these supplies
都不翼而飞了?
start getting out to the fleet?
目标空间跳跃引擎已被摧毁 看你们的了
The target's FTL is history. She's all yours.
他没事
RACETRACK: He's all right!
我再说一遍 阿波罗没事
RACETRACK: I say again, Apollo is all right.
就让我们为都能活着回来而高兴吧 好吗?
Let's just be glad that we both came back alive, all right?
我就是因为这个感到对不起你  卡拉
That's just it, Kara.
我当时不想再活着回来了
I didn't want to make it back alive.
你不会开枪的
You're not gonna shoot.
你和我不一样
You're not like me.
嗨 嗨!  嗨 别走
APOLLO: Hey, hey. Hey, don't go.
对不起 我以为你还没醒
Sorry. I thought you were still asleep.
你应该在一小时前把我踢下床
You should have kicked me out of bed an hour ago.
如果我再占用卡拉迪加的运输机 泰会要我好看
If I hold up Galactica's Raptor, Tigh'll have my ass.
它现在属于我
Which, we both know, currently belongs to me.
好吧 我们讨论下一个议题
All right, let's move on to the next item.
不 先生们 请别站起来
Oh, no, gentlemen, please, don't get up.
床上躺了这几周 站着感觉真好
After the last few weeks, it just feels good to be on my feet.
谢谢
Thank you, though.
总统女士 你恢复的非常好
You've made a remarkable recovery, Madam President.
非常好 是的  但是现在我要赶进度了
Remarkable indeed. But now I'm playing catch-up.
生病的时候 注意力有些分散
I'm afraid during my illness I lost focus. I let some things slide.
现在已经过去了
Well, that's behind us now.
是的 我想说的是物资供应紧张 人们都很担心
Yes, it is. To the point. Supplies are running low and the people are worried.
平民嘛
FISK: Well, they wouldn't be civilians
总是喜欢说三道四的
if they didn't have something to bitch about.
我想在这个问题上他们还是有权利的
ROSLIN: Well, I think that in this case, they're entitled.
军队供应有些紧张 但还没到危险的地步
Our inventory levels are tight, but they're not critical.
但是整个舰队
But all the way across the fleet,
都在报告重要物资短缺
people are reporting shortages of essential goods,
或者只能以高价买到
and what they do get comes at a high price.
他们转向黑市
They're turning to the black market.
上周我一个助手生肺炎
Last week, one of my aides came down with pneumonia.
比利只能用酒来换抗生素
Billy had to trade liquor to get the antibiotics.
这很动物本能 人们会想方设法得到想要的东西
It's the nature of the beast. People want what they want.
少量交易是一码事  菲斯克指挥官  这是现实
A few trades would be one thing, Commander Fisk. That's reality.
我所说的是罪犯
But I'm talking about criminals
利用物资短缺 从中非法渔利
making outrageous demands on the people.
所以我要制定一个新贸易政策作为底线
So, bottom line is, I'm implementing a new, fleet-wide trade policy.
应该由我们来控制物资供给 而不是黑市的恶棍
We need to be in control of our supply chain, not black market thugs.
我希望在这个问题上能得到军方的支持
I am hoping that I can have the military's support on this.
上将 如果你想在珀加索斯上抓这些家伙 只管下令
Admiral, if you want Pegasus to run these dogs down, you just give us the word.
我们会尽力使情况得到控制
Our people will do whatever it takes to get this under control.
总统女士 很高兴你又回来了
And it's good to have you back, Madam President.
能回来很高兴  谢谢上将
It's good to be back. Thank you, Admiral.
先生们  谢谢
Gentlemen, thank you.
总统女士总是这么直接的吗?
FISK: Is Madam President always so right-in-your-face?
最后一分钟的"复活"多少使她变得精力充沛
Her last-minute resurrection seems to have invigorated her somewhat.
也许充沛过头了
Yeah, well, maybe too much.
她不会真认为一个规定…
She doesn't really think her made-up plans and regulations
能改变什么吧?
are gonna change anything, does she?
怕我们没事干
As if we don't have enough to do.
但是总统现在有很高的声望
No, Madam President sets a great prestige by her office
还有阿达玛的支持
and Adama supports her, at least for the moment.
还有我的支持 当然只是目前
Well, then, so do I, just for the moment.
顺便问一下 收到我送的雪茄了吗?
By the way, did you get the cigars I had sent over?
我不但已经收到 而且已经抽过了
I not only got them, I enjoyed them as well.
这是我的荣幸 副总统先生
Well, my pleasure, Mr. Vice President.
好了 我还要回去管理帕加索斯
Well, I've got a ship to run.
希望能再次见到你
I look forward to our next visit.
我也是
As do I.
一个朋友给我的
SHEVON: I got them from a friend.
帕雅    嗨 宝贝儿
APOLLO: Paya. SHEVON: Hey, sweetie.
哇 每次我见到你 你都长高了些
Wow. You seem to get an inch taller every time I see you.
怎么 不愿意和我握手吗?
What, I don't get my handshake?
这没关系  帕雅
Well, that's okay, Paya.
我有个特别惊喜给你 就在这里面
I have a special surprise for you, and it's in here.
想过来看看吗?
APOLLO: You wanna come see?
看看有什么?
SHEVON: What's he got? Go on.
APOLLO: What have we got?
哦  帕雅
Oh, Paya.
我不太会和孩子相处
I've never been great with kids.
也许下次能找个有两个眼睛的
Maybe next time I'll get one with two eyes.
我会看看还能买点什么
I'll see if I can trade it for something else.
不 这很好  你已经带给她惊喜了
No, it's okay. You just surprised her.
好吧
Well...
你看 我不知道什么时候才能再来
Well, look, I'm not sure when I'll be able to make it back.
我知道
I know.
因为你过了夜 我还要多收你100元
I'm gonna have to ask for an extra hundred since you spent the night.
我正在想你怎么还不露头
Well, I wondered when you were gonna show up.
猛禽129  允许进入
LANDING OFFICER:Raptor one-two-niner,
允许进入
you are cleared into the break.
卡拉狄加  猛禽129 一切正常
RACETRACK: Galactica, Raptor one-two-niner has the ball.
进入速度  220
Inbound speed 220.
上将 上校  我正要开始
Admiral, Colonel, I'm just getting started,
但是根据经验  他是窒息而死
but from the looks of him, I'd say he was garroted.
神啊 我们现在最怕这种事发生
Gods. This is the last thing we needed.
上将 你也许想看看这个
Admiral, you might want to take a look at this.
看来我们的朋友菲斯克中奖了
Looks like our friend Fisk hit the jackpot.
发现其它东西 马上通知我
Cubit? If you find anything else, let me know right away.
再发现其它东西 我可能要提早退休了
If I find anything else, I may retire early.
有人在警告我们
ADAMA: Someone's sending us a message.
也许只是旧事重演
Or running us in circles.
也许舰队里还有赛昂人
Maybe there's another Cylon in the fleet.
我倒希望如此 好过自相残杀
I'd almost prefer that to the alternative: we start killing our own.
我们要做的就是静观其变
All they have to do is sit back and watch.
菲斯克?
Fisk?
知道谁干的吗?
Do we have any idea who did it?
不
No.
但我们要做一个全面调查 我希望你来负责
But we will do a full investigation and I want you to lead it.
我觉得应该…
Don't you think it would be better
让珀加索斯的人来干比较合适?
if someone from Pegasus dealt with this?
虽然凯恩死了 她的影响还在
Even though Cain's gone, her influence lingers.
我需要我可以信任的人
I need someone I can trust.
你知道曾经有段时间 我们之间缺少信任
You know, there were times when that was in short supply between us.
我们都经历了不少
We've both been through an awful lot, Son.
我希望我们因此变得更坚强
And I hope that we've grown stronger for it.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我马上飞去珀加索斯
I'll call up a flight to Pegasus right away.
有人进去过吗?
Anyone else been inside?
只有医疗队 长官
Just the medical team, sir.
知道我是谁吗? 我是副总统 让我进去!
BALTAR: Do you know who I am? I am the Vice President of the Colonies. Let me in
阿达玛上校
Captain Adama.
菲斯克指挥官没说也邀请了你
Commander Fisk didn't tell me you were invited.
让他进来
Let him in.
他们正想让我进去
They were going to let me in.
哦 我的神啊
BALTAR: Oh, my gods.
发生了什么?
What's going on in here?
菲斯克在哪里?
Where's Fisk?
在卡拉狄加停尸房的桌子上
On a slab in Galactica's morgue.
他死了?
What, he's dead?
这是你抽的雪茄烟牌子吗?
Isn't this your brand?
当心 盖尤斯
NO. 6: Careful, Gaius.
拯救罗丝林带给你一些好名声
You bought yourself some goodwill by saving Roslin,
但它正在消失
but it's fading.
他们对你有所怀疑
Their old suspicions are reemerging.
你在这里干吗?
What are you doing here?
上校?
Captain?
我正要问你同样的问题
I was about to ask you the same thing.
等会
Wait a minute, I...
你在审问我?
Are you interrogating me?
我不喜欢你的用辞
I'm not sure I appreciate your tone.
这可不是在上外交课 有人被杀了
This isn't a diplomatic exercise. A man was butchered.
他的脑袋是被钢琴弦勒的快脱离了身子
APOLLO: His head was practically severed from his body with piano wire.
你是舰队副总统
NO. 6: You're Vice President of the fleet.
为什么表现得像偷饼干被抓的小孩?
Why are you acting like a child with your hand in the cookie jar, hmm?
你知道看到你这样 她会说什么?
Wonder what she would say if she saw you like this.
你看我并不需要向你解释什么?
You know, I can't believe it's even necessary for me to explain myself to you,
但是很明显 我和菲斯克指挥官的死毫无关系
but obviously, no, I had nothing to do with Commander Fisk's death.
我只是想过来他谈谈…
For the record, I just came here to discuss
罗丝林总统的新贸易政策
President Roslin's new trade policy.
我以为那个已经达成一致了
Well, I thought that was settled.
不 菲斯克指挥官有些不同意见
No, Commander Fisk had some reservations.
我肯定他会有的!
I'll bet.
作为副总统
And as the Vice President,
我决定来打消他的疑虑
I decided to assuage his doubts of my own free will.
满意了?
Is that sufficient?
或者我可以给你提供一个不在场证明?
Or would you like me to provide you with an alibi?
我肯定可以找到
I'm sure I can rustle one up.
抽你的雪茄吧
Enjoy the cigars.
把副总统护送回他的船
APOLLO: Escort the Vice President to his ship.
无线电快疯了
The wireless is going crazy.
全都是关于菲斯克的死
Word of Fisk's murder has spread out through the entire fleet.
当一个指挥官在战舰上被杀
When we lose a command officer aboard a warship,
人们会担心安全问题
people are gonna be concerned about their security.
船员会因为失去指挥官而陷入混乱
TIGH: A crew can fall apart when their commander's killed.
珀加索斯在几周内失去了两个指挥官
Pegasus lost two in a matter of weeks.
也许这次是他们的运气
Maybe this time they were lucky.
他的个人日志表明未经授权的装卸
His personal log shows that he was rerouting supply runs,
转运补给品
on and offloading freighters without command authorization.
并且在上周就非法查抄了
APOLLO: He raided the MacConnel
麦康诺尔等十几只船
and at least a dozen other ships in the last week.
我还在他住处发现了小仓库里面有很多高价值的货品
I found a small warehouse of high-value merchandise in his quarters.
他在搞黑市
He was working the black market.
半个舰队都在搞  菲斯克变得越来越贪婪
Half the fleet's working it. Fisk was getting greedy.
如果他和他的某个供应商发生矛盾
If he crossed one of his suppliers on a deal,
就能解释卡特尔医生找到的东西了
that would explain the cubits that Cottle found.
依然不能证明谁干的
It still doesn't tell us who did it.
他肯定有交易伙伴
Well, he's gonna need trading partners.
这并不难找  即使是在卡拉狄加上
And they wouldn't be hard to find, even on Galactica.
好吧 咱们打开看看
WORKER 1: All right, let's open it up here.
拿回去
WORKER 2: Move around back.
李  我很害怕
Lee, I'm scared.
帕雅的咳嗽越来越厉害
Paya's cough keeps getting worse.
我下次来给你带点东西
I'll bring her something on my next trip.
那可能要几个礼拜  如果又有赛昂人袭击的话
Which could be weeks if there's another Cylon attack.
我经常听说舰队物资短缺
I keep hearing about shortages on the other ships,
人们用任何可以交易的东西来交换食物和药物
people trading anything they can for food, and for medicine.
是吗?
Really?
你没看到外面那些新露面的女孩子吗?
Have you seen all the new working girls outside?
李  当你的孩子因为饥饿而哭喊
Lee, when your baby's crying because it's hungry,
你会做任何事来停止他们的哭喊
you'll do anything to make it stop.
嗨
Hey.
过来
Come here.
妈咪!
PAYA: Mommy.
上校?
Captain.
想干吗?
What do you want?
你妻子在吗 上校?
APOLLO: Is your wife around, Colonel?
不 怎么?
No. Why?
这是你的吗?
Is this hers?
是的 几周前掉了
Yeah. She lost it a couple weeks ago.
你在哪里找到的?
Where the hell did you find it?
在珀加索斯
On Pegasus.
在菲斯克指挥官的住处
In Commander Fisk's quarters.
她烧的很厉害!
She's burning up.
医务室的人怎么说?
APOLLO: What did they say at the infirmary?
所有抗生素都分配掉了
Antibiotics have all been rationed out.
可能在周末会有一些
They said they might have something by the end of the week.
整个舰队都面临物质短缺 好多人在讨残羹剩饭吃
We got shortages across the fleet, people begging for scraps,
而你和泰夫人还有新鲜水果和真的酒
but somehow you and Mrs. Tigh have fresh fruit, real liquor...
好么  这到底是什么意思?
All right. What the hell is this about?
你肯定知道她和菲斯克作交易
You must have known she was trading with Fisk.
要不我还是和她说
Well, maybe I'll talk to her.
不是她 是我  我只是交换一些必需品
She didn't give it to Fisk. I did. I traded it for a few necessities,
和一些她需要的东西 有什么大不了的!
a couple of things to help her get by. Big frakking deal.
没有任何不合法的地方
There's nothing illegal about that.
目前为止
Not yet.
别装的道貌岸然
Don't you play holier-than-thou with me.
我还没做过这船上很多人做过的事
I haven't done anything that most people on this ship haven't done.
包括你
Including you.
很多人做着错事
Doesn't make us right, Colonel,
并不意味这就是对的
just a whole lot of people wrong.
今天你没来上课
You didn't make it to class today.
是的 我很忙
Yeah, I've been pretty jammed up.
而且 我想你不需要我再握住你的手
Anyway, I'm not sure you need me holding your hand anymore.
这就是你上课的目的?  就为了握住我的手?
Was that what you were doing? Holding my hand?
就当作是赞赏
I meant it as a compliment.
请求发言 长官
Permission to speak frankly, sir?
你不需要我允许 你也不需要说长官
You don't need my permission and you don't need the "sir. "
也许这就是问题所在 我不知道到底在想什么
Maybe that's the problem. I don't really know what to think anymore.
所以 我就问 这会有什么结果吗?
So I'll just ask. Is this going somewhere?
小杜
Dee...
请不要装作不知道我在说什么
Please don't pretend like you don't know what I'm talking about.
我们在一起的时间 我们一起练习
You now, our... Our time together, our workouts.
我们的关系有些变化
Something's changed between us.
我不知道你想让我怎么说
I'm just not sure what you want me to say.
那就什么也不要说
Then don't say anything.
阿达玛上校有人呼叫!
WOMAN:Communications paging Captain Adama.
星云九号来的紧急电话
You have a priority ship-to-ship call from Cloud 9.
我是阿达玛上校
Captain Adama here.
雪雯!
APOLLO: Shevon.
雪雯  是我!
Shevon, it's me!
雪雯!
Shevon?
哦 天哪  他们做了什么?
Oh, my gods. What did they do?
他们说知道你和我的事!
They said they knew about you and me.
他们想知道我们谈了些什么
They wanted to know what we've been talking about.
李 我不知道他们为什么关心这个!
Lee, I don't understand why they'd care.
好吧  带上需要的东西  我带你和帕雅回卡拉狄加
All right, get what you need. I'm taking you and Paya back to Galactica.
李 等一下!
Lee, wait.
那里是唯一我可以保证你们安全的地方
It's the only place I can keep you safe.
你想怎么和他们说我们的关系?
What are you gonna tell them about us?
我不想欺骗我自己 我知道这是什么
I'm not fooling myself. I know what this is.
李!
SHEVON: Lee!
别过来!
Get away from us!
听着吗?
You listening?
再管菲斯克的事
I hear any more talk about Fisk,
我会把那婊子切碎了还给你
I'm going to send your whore back to you piece by piece.
我会从那个小女孩开始
And then I'm gonna start on the little girl.
我知道你是谁 我知道你是谁的儿子
I know who you are, I know whose son you are.
但我不在乎
And I don't care.
你告诉阿达玛别再查了
You tell Adama to let it go.
你是不是知道你爱她?
Is that when you knew that you loved her?
是的
I thought so.
但是你伤害了她
SHEVON: But you hurt her.
我是阿达玛上校
This is Captain Adama.
我需要一个医生和警卫 越快越好
I need a medic and a security team on L Deck asap.
你想见我 总统女士?
You wanted to see me, Madam President?
是的
Yes.
谢谢你能来 博士
Thank you for coming, Doctor.
请坐
Have a seat.
来点茶?
Would you like some tea?
好的
I'd love one.
我一直对我们之间的关系感到困惑
You know, I'm never quite sure where we stand with each other, Doctor.
你觉得是为什么呢?
Why do you think that is?
我不知道
I can't imagine why.
我对你及你的政府都非常尊敬
I've never had anything but the utmost respect for you and your office.
我知道在菲斯克指挥官死前
I understand that you and Commander Fisk planned to meet
你正打算和他会面
just prior to his death.
正如我已经和阿达玛上校说过的那样
As I have already explained to Captain Adama,
菲斯克指挥官对你的新贸易政策有些疑问
Commander Fisk had several lingering concerns about your new trade policy.
我还能说什么呢
What can I say?
就这么简单?
And that's it?
盖尤斯 她有点怕你
NO. 6: Gaius, she's afraid of you.
为什么
Why
你要问这些呢?
are you asking me this?
你救了我的命 我很感激
You saved my life and I'm grateful.
但是我感觉…
But I sense that there is some unease in you
你履行总统职责有些困难
about assuming the presidency
所以我想让你退出
and I'd like to offer you an out.
你说什么?
You what?
辞职
Resign.
回卡拉狄加上继续从事你的研究工作
Return to your scientific work on Galactica.
没人会质疑你的动机
No one will question your motives,
你可以把这个看作第二次机会 正如你给我这次机会一样
and you can consider it a second chance like the one you gave me.
太好了
Charming.
博士?
Doctor,
这是你唯一的机会
this is a one-time offer.
我建议你再考虑一下
I suggest you reconsider.
总统女士  我对政治从来没有什么特别大的兴趣
You know, Madam President, I've never been particularly interested in politics
我对权力同样没有兴趣
and I never wanted any lofty position of power.
我从来就没想过要当副总统
I never wanted to be the Vice President.
但是 现在不同了
That is, until this very moment.
因为现在 我想不到有什么东西比这个更重要
Because right now, I can't think of anything I want more.
头上吃了一枪    不是你干的?
One to the head. You didn't do this?
我被攻击了 我醒来他就在那里了
I was attacked. I found him there when I woke up.
法医说菲斯克就是被线给勒死了
Security bulletin said Commander Fisk was garroted with a wire.
不管发生了什么  你应该是找到了真凶
Whatever happened, looks like you found your guy.
雪雯怎么样了?  还有她的女儿?
What about Shevon, and her daughter?
星云九号是个开放港口 可能他们已经离开了
Cloud 9's an open port. Chances are they're already off-ship.
我去叫人
I'll get a team down here.
查莱克议员
Councilman Zarek.
李 我刚听说 你还好吗?
Lee. I just heard. Are you all right?
你来干吗?
What are you doing here?
参加一个法人会议
Attending a Quorum meeting.
没什么比这个更令人兴奋的
Nothing as exciting as all this, I assure you.
这个地方是非法的
I know these places are legal, but still,
但是伟大的阿达玛的儿子却在这里
the son of the almighty Adama?
跟我说说黑市的情况吧
Talk to me about the black market.
没什么好说的 到处都有 无法避免
Not much to say. It's widespread, inevitable,
根据罗丝林总统说是非法的
and according to President Roslin, illegal.
那就不奇怪菲斯克和你搞在一起直到掉脑袋了
So it's no surprise that you and Fisk were in it up to your necks.
菲斯克会 但我不会
Fisk, maybe, but not me.
我是星际皇后号的代表 我必须注意交往对象
I represent Astral Queen. Have to be careful about the company I keep.
这是菲斯克的日志
This is Fisk's log.
上面说在过去10天他去了星际皇后号三次
He says he made three runs to Astral Queen in the last 10 days
我想你们不会是在讨论监狱改革吧
and I doubt it was to discuss prison reform.
你想怎么样 上校?
What do you want from me, Captain?
船名 联系人
Names of ships. Contacts.
我帮不了你
I can't help you.
你认为菲斯克为什么来找我?
Why do you think Fisk approached me?
想从你的黑市买卖分点好处  给你提供保护
To get a piece of your black market scam. To offer you protection.
你和你老爸都喜欢用老眼光看人
You and your father are both so blinded by the past.
菲斯克的黑市在你找我之前 就已经在运作了
Fisk's black market was up and running when he approached me.
他知道阿达玛早晚会发现那些未授权的飞行
He knew Adama would pick up on his unauthorized shuttles,
他想强迫我来帮他运输
so he tried to force me into taking over the deliveries,
在帕伽索斯和非法运输船只之间建立一道"防火墙"
creating a firewall between Pegasus and the illegal shipments.
你想告诉我 你拒绝了?
So you're trying to tell me that you turned him down?
代价很大
At great cost.
查一下日志
Check the fleet logs,
从菲斯克最后一次离开后 有几艘补给船来过星际皇后号
see how many supply ships made stops at the Astral Queen after Fisk's last trip
答案是没有
The answer is none.
既然菲斯克想饿死你
So if Fisk was trying to starve you out,
为什么你不告诉法人团?
why didn't you bring it to the Quorum?
罗丝林弄得好像黑市是件什么大不了的事
Roslin's acting like the black market's some sort of aberration,
我觉得你应该比她聪明
but I thought you were smarter than that.
你真觉得
Did you really expect
会有什么乌托邦幻想能无中生有?
some utopian fantasy to rise from the ashes?
我听警卫说了
ZAREK: I heard the security officer.
他们把杀死菲斯克的人交给你是有原因的
They gave you Fisk's killer for a reason.
他们给了你条退路
They're offering you a way out.
你知道些什么 对吗?
You know something, don't you?
只是些谣言
Just rumors.
有艘运输船 普罗米修斯号
There's a freighter, Prometheus.
有人说它只是运谷物的
Some people say it's gone off the grid.
但你非常想要某些东西
But if you want something bad enough,
就该去那里
that's where you go.
交易都由一个退役的雇佣兵控制他名叫菲朗
The deals are brokered by an ex-military mercenary named Phelan.
李
Lee.
我希望她值得你这么干
I hope she's worth it.
抗生素要不要!
Hey, man, biotics. Here.
帕雅!
Paya?
帕雅! 帕雅! 嗨  帕雅!
Paya! Paya! Hey, Paya.
嗨!  没关系
Hey, it's okay.
我是李 记得吗 我是李
It's Lee, do you remember? It's Lee.
你会没事的 我向你保证
You're gonna be fine, I promise you.
稍微等会 我马上回来 我马上回来
Okay, you just hang tight. I'll be right back. I'll be right back.
也许你觉得很难相信 我父亲也曾经是军人
You may find this hard to believe, but my father was in the service, too.
非常严格 也许和你父亲一样
Strict as hell, probably the same as your old man.
但是当赛昂人袭击时 他正好在执勤
But when the Cylons attacked, all his duty and honor didn't add up to squat.
她死了?
Is she dead?
我知道你为什么想要她 她是我这里最好的之一
I can see why you want her back. She's one of my best.
你的什么?
One of yours?
除了做爱之外 她还懂得…
A good escort understands it's about a lot more than sex.
什么时候去倾听  什么时候去求助
PHELAN: She knows when to listen, and when to call for help.
李 我被迫的
Lee, I had to.
别怪她
PHELAN: Don't blame her.
你还能活着的唯一原因
The only reason you're alive
就是我可以通过雪雯监视你
is because I was able to see you through Shevon's eyes.
我觉得你应该比较通情达理
And what I saw seemed reasonable.
象菲斯克?
Like Fisk?
菲斯克是头猪
Fisk was a pig.
他想强迫我们重新谈判
He tried to force us to renegotiate.
所以你杀了他
So you killed him.
不 我把凶手交给了你
No. I gave you the killer,
还有凶器 指纹
the murder weapon, the prints,
一切你所需要的能够合法地结案的东西
everything you needed to close the case legitimately.
尽管总统反对 但舰队需要我们
Despite the President's objections, the fleet needs us.
配给太少 运输船来的太慢  我们就像减压阀
Rationing's too tight, ship comes in too late, we're the pressure valve.
我们来供应
We provide.
比如雪雯需要抗生素 她就知道去哪里找
PHELAN: When Shevon needed antibiotics, she knew where to go.
没有我们  人们无法得到满足
Without us, people would have nowhere to turn.
整个舰队就会陷入混乱
The fleet would tear itself apart.
外面那些孩子呢?
And what about those children outside?
你要他们
How are they
对舰队有什么帮助?
helping the fleet?
每个人都有自己的需要
Everyone has needs.
有人喜欢雪茄 有人需要酒
Some settle for cigars and liquor.
你想要雪雯
You wanted Shevon.
其他人还有更多需求
Others are more demanding.
我们都各有所需
It's hard to find the moral high ground
所以很难对别人的道德有过高要求
when we're all standing in the mud.
我不象迈克  我父亲 上校
I'm not like my old man, Captain.
你也不象你父亲
And you are not like yours.
我一个人来的
I came alone,
但卡拉狄加在雷达上跟踪我
but Galactica tracked me on dradis.
他们所需要的就是找个借口干掉这艘船
All they'll need to vent this ship into space is an excuse.
所以  我们还是做个交易
So let's make a deal.
我需要雪雯  我们离开这里
I want Shevon, the girl, I walk out of here
然后你停止这项买卖
and you shut down this operation.
我就当什么也没发生
And all of you will live.
对不起  那个小女孩有预定了 不能退款了
Sorry, the little girl's been paid for. No refunds.
哦 天啊!  不要!
Oh, gods. No!
等会!  李 不要!
PHELAN: Wait. Lee, don't.
来啊 开枪!  开枪!
Come on. Do it. Do it.
我给了你个公平买卖
I made you a fair offer.
我也是
So did I.
也许你所说的都是对的
APOLLO: Yeah, you're probably right about everything.
你 我 菲斯克
You, me, Fisk.
没人能关掉黑市 也许本来就不该关掉
Nobody can stop it. And maybe nobody should.
但必须要有限度
But it needs limits.
有些限制你不能跨越 而你跨过去了
There's lines you can't cross and you've crossed them.
你不会开枪的
You're not gonna shoot.
你和我不一样
You're not like me.
你不会
You're not gonna...
好了 到此为止
APOLLO: All right, it's done.
舰队需要黑市
The fleet relies on the black market.
不管怎么说 我们需要它
Much as we'd like, we can't wish that away.
所以 你们可以继续你们的买卖
So you're still in business.
暂时
For now.
但是再有杀人
But if there are any more killings,
再有囤积重要药品的
if you hold back essential medicines,
如果你们再打孩子的主意
if you ever touch a child...
雪雯
Shevon...
不要
No, I don't want...
嗨  结束了  没事了
Hey, hey, it's over. It's okay. Everything's gonna be okay...
李 不要     雪雯 都结束了
Lee, Lee, no. Hey. Shevon, it's over.
住手
Stop.
我不能变成你想让我变成的人
I can't be what you want me to be.
我并不想让你变成任何人
I don't want you to be anything.
你想让我变成她
You want me to be her.
你一直就是这么想的
That's what this is about.
一直就是这样
That's what this has always been about.
不 并非一直就是这样
No. That's not what this has ever been about.
得了 李 我知道我的工作
Come on, Lee. I know my job.
我只是个替代品
I'm a replacement.
替代很多东西
For a lot of things.
那些你无法从其它地方得到的东西
Things that men can't get anywhere else.
那些你失去的东西
SHEVON: Things they've lost.
她想给你生个孩子!
She wanted to give you a child.
但是你害怕
But you were afraid,
所以你拒绝了她 然后你逃避
so you pushed her away and then you ran,
直到一切都太晚了 你才停止逃避
and you didn't stop running until it was too late.
但我不是她!
Well, I'm not her.
帕雅不是也永远不会变成你的孩子
And Paya is not, and will never be, your child.
菲斯克谋杀案已经破了
APOLLO: Commander Fisk's murder has been resolved
帕伽索斯的船员们看上去已经接受了卡拉狄加的结论
and Pegasus' crew appears to have accepted Galactica's conclusions.
就这样 总统女士
That's all, Madam President.
不完全是 普罗米修斯号怎么办?
Not quite. What about this ship Prometheus?
我知道那是整个舰队黑市的中心
I understand it's the hub of the fleet's black market.
我们会继续关注它们
We will keep an eye on them.
关注它们?
Keep an eye on them.
我可不是这么想的
That's not exactly the solution I had in mind.
让一个犯罪企业在舰队中发展
Whether or not we allow a criminal enterprise to thrive in this fleet
那可不行 上校
is not a matter of choice, Captain.
上将?
Admiral?
这事我完全交给李
I've given Lee full authority on this issue.
这是他的决定
The decision is his.
我真心支持你的新贸易政策  总统女士
I support your trade policies wholeheartedly, Madam President,
但我们永远也不会有一个完美制度
but we are never gonna have a perfect system.
总会有某些形式的黑市存在
There will always be some kind of black market.
至少现在 我知道名字 知道他们长什么样  知道他们在哪里
At least this way I know names, I know faces, I know where they are
我们会监视他们的
and we will monitor the situation.
谢谢 先生们 我很忙
Thank you, gentlemen, I'm busy.
18  我要出点汗  19...
BILLY: Eighteen. I'm starting to sweat here. Nineteen...
你也应该流下汗 20…
You should be sweating. Twenty...
为什么你不练这些
Why aren't you doing any of these?
别说话
No talking, no talking, please.
别作弊 举高点
No cheating. Hold it up, a little higher.
无耻 8 9…
Sneaky. Eight, nine...
再来 你太不认真了
Start again. You aren't serious.
零…
Zero...
不来?
Well? No?
总统今天不太高兴
President wasn't very happy today.
是的
No.
自从你从黑鸟上弹射出来后  你就变了
Ever since you ejected from the Blackbird, you've been different.
很难找到你
Harder to reach.
我只是想知道
I'm just trying to understand.
正如你所说  父亲  我们都经历了不少
Well, like you said, Dad, we've all been through a lot.
是啊
Fair enough.
但你应该告诉我那个女人的事
But you should have told me about the woman.